

# Janick Georg Weberpals Real World Data Scientist

Born 30 April 1989, in Bruchsal, Germany

janickweberpals.github.io

+1 (857) 381-7865 LinkedIn Profile

janick.weberpals@me.com

# About me ———

Janick Weberpals, RPh, Ph.D., is a real world data (RWD) scientist with 8+ years of experience in the design and conduct of studies in large non-randomized healthcare databases in both industry and academia. He holds a pharmacy degree from Philipps-University Marburg, a board certification as specialized pharmacist in drug information and a Ph.D. in Epidemiology from the University of Heidelberg, Germany. He is interested in methods to analyze high-dimensional electronic healthcare databases and integrate data modalities (images, free text) using deep learning for the application to real-world problems in causal inference. He (co-) authored 20+ peer-reviewed high-impact publications and received several awards.

# Skills ———

SQL

Python

Tensorflow, Keras

SAS

Education

2018-2020 Postdoctoral Fellowship Data Science, Roche Innovation Center Munich Deep learning on electronic health record (EHR) data

2015-2018 Ph.D. Epidemiology Medical Faculty, University of Heidelberg

Summa cum laude honors

2015-2018 Board certification German Cancer Research Center, Heidelberg Specialized Pharmacist in Drug Information

2010-2015 Registered Pharmacist (RPh) College of Pharmacy, University of Marburg Pharmaceutical Sciences (PharmD equivalent)

### Professional Experience

2022-Instructor in Medicine Harvard Medical School, Boston, MA Faculty member leading projects on multimodal healthcare database analytics and comparative effectiveness and safety research.

2022-**Associate Scientist** Brigham and Women's Hospital, Boston, MA Division of Pharmacoepidemiology and Pharmacoeconomics, Department of Medicine.

2020-2022 **Data Scientist** Hoffmann-La Roche/Genentech, Basel, Switzerland Lead on multiple health studies in oncology and neuroscience. Collaborated in cross-functional teams to validate ML/NLP algorithms to enhance data elements which supported clinical teams with regulatory drug applications. Contributed to R package development which increased speed and validity of real-world evidence projects.

2019-now Medical Faculty, University of Heidelberg, Germany Conceptualization and teaching of an introductory course on design and biases of epidemiological studies for Biostatistics M.Sc. students.

2018-2020 Postdoctoral Fellow in Deep Learning on EHR Roche, Munich, Germany Development of deep learning methods to analyze large electronic health record (EHR) databases to optimize and complement clinical trials.

2015-2018 **Doctoral Researcher** German Cancer Research Center, Heidelberg, Germany Analysis of large oncological database linkages by partnering with international cancer registries which resulted in 14 high-impact publications.

2014-2015 Research Scholar University of Florida, Gainesville, FL, USA Contributed to a multidisciplinary project to develop a *predictive* risk model to identify adverse events among hospitalized patients.

#### Selected Awards & Honors

2018 Stephan-Weiland Award (German Society for Epidemiology)

Advancement Award for best Ph.D. thesis in Epidemiology (German 2018

Association for Medical Informatics, Biometry and Epidemiology)

2017 Poster Award (Helmholtz International Graduate School)

2016 & 17 International Society for Pharmacoepidemiology (ISPE) Scholarship

2016 Fellow (Helmholtz International Graduate School)

Selected publications (Visit janickweberpals.github.io/scholarship for a full report)

Weberpals J, Becker T, Schmich F, Ruettinger D, Theis FJ, Bauer-Mehren A. Deep learning-based propensity scores for confounding control in comparative effectiveness research: a large-scale real-world data study. Epidemiology (2021).

Loureiro H, Becker T, Bauer-Mehren A, Ahmidi N, Weberpals J. Artificial Intelligence for Prognostic Scores in Oncology: a benchmarking study. Frontiers in Artificial Intelligence (2021).